IAN EVERITT

127 W 10th St, #302, Kansas City, MO 64105 · (269) 206-6309 <u>ian.andrew.everitt@gmail.com</u> · <u>LinkedIn Profile</u> <u>GitHub Profile</u> · My Portfolio

Full stack web developer with experience developing clean and intuitive user interfaces using React, TypeScript, and JavaScript on the front end, powered by Node and Express engines and MySQL databases on the back end. I look forward to being an effective member of a team dedicated to empowering communities through the products we create and the technology we innovate.

EXPERIENCE

NOVEMBER 2021 – PRESENT

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER, ENCHANTED QUILL ARTWORK

Full stack developer building an ecommerce site for Enchanted Quill Artwork according to provided wireframe and user stories. This site is hosted on Heroku, and it uses React, TypeScript, Node, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, and Cloudinary for image hosting.

Visit current site: https://calm-oasis-15641.herokuapp.com/

Owner: Rebecca Stone | enchantedquillartwork@gmail.com | (810) 360-5703

SEPTEMBER 2018 – DECEMBER 2020

INSTRUCTOR, DEPARTMENT OF PHILOSOPHY, WESTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY

Instructor of record for a total of nine undergraduate courses over five semesters. This included designing, teaching, and grading courses such as Critical Thinking, Biomedical Ethics, Environmental Ethics, Contemporary Problems in Ethics, Introduction to Ethics, and Science, Technology and Values.

Department Chair: David Paul | david.paul@wmich.edu | (269) 387-4367

MAY 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018

ASSISTANT MANAGER, TACO BOB'S

Supervised restaurant on day-to-day basis. Duties included staff scheduling and delegation of daily responsibilities. Staff maintenance also included training, hiring, and terminating employees. Other duties included managing inventory levels, taking food orders, cooking, and bartending. General Manager: Alexander Hoffman | golddeucegoose@gmail.com | (269) 978-0776

EDUCATION

JANUARY 2021 - JULY 2021

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE, MSU CODING BOOTCAMP

Front-end and back-end web development with a focus on up-to-date best practices using JavaScript, React, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node, Express, MySQL, and MongoDB. See my portfolio for an up-to-date look at my best projects.

SEPTEMBER 2018 – JUNE 2021

MASTER'S DEGREE, WESTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY

GPA: 4.00

I completed coursework for my master's degree in analytic philosophy at WMU where I've achieved a deeper appreciation and mastery of critical thinking and problem solving. Here, I've had the privilege of researching ethical theory and moral development, and I'm happy to have had the opportunity to publish some of my own research.

SEPTEMBER 2014 - APRIL 2018

BACHELOR'S DEGREE, WESTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY

GPA: 3.39

Bachelor of arts in philosophy

- ♦ Maintained a 4.00 GPA in the second half of my undergraduate career
- 2018 WMU Presidential Scholar Award recipient
 - The highest honor WMU bestows on its undergraduates
- President of WMU Undergraduate Philosophy Club, January 2017 April 2018

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- React
- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- ◆ CSS
- HTML
- **❖** GSAP
- Bootstrap

- Bulma
- ❖ Node.js
- Express.js
- MySQL/Sequelize
- MongoDB/Mongoose
- ❖ Git
- Heroku

PROJECTS

React | JavaScript | Bootstrap | Node.js | Express.js | MySQL | Sequelize

INSPECTO-GADGET

Full stack React application my peers and I created to be used by the city of Orchard Lake, Michigan. This app allows inspectors and administrators to see and update all past, present, and upcoming building inspections. My primary role was creating front-end UI and UX React components and updating these components in response to user feedback.

Visit MVP site: https://arcane-taiga-84005.herokuapp.com/. Username: Electrical Pass: pass12345

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | GSAP | JavaScript | Node.js | Express.js | MySQL | Sequelize GROUP MENTALITY

Full stack forum application that allows users to interact with mental health experts via forums. Mental health experts (i.e., moderators) can edit, respond to, and delete user messages. My primary role was writing back-end routing and front-end requests to the server.

Visit our site: https://protected-waters-68869.herokuapp.com/

HTML | CSS | Bulma | jQuery | BreweryDB API | REFUGE Restrooms REST API GOOD BREWS AND NEUTRAL LOOS

With this application, users search a city for a list of local breweries. For each brewery, it is indicated whether the brewery has a gender-neutral bathroom; if not, the user can click a button to reveal the nearest gender-neutral bathroom to that brewery. My primary role was creating the API requests and managing their responses on the front end.

Visit our site: https://rflctveq.github.io/brews-and-loos/

LEADERSHIP ROLES

*	Graduate Student Mentor for the WMU Philosophy Department	Apr 2019 – Apr 2020
*	Vice President of the Graduate Student Association of Philosophers	Apr 2019 – Apr 2020
*	Graduate Advisor for WMU's Undergraduate Ethics Bowl Team	Sep 2019 – Jan 2020
*	President of the WMU Undergraduate Philosophy Club	Jan 2017 – Apr 2018

INTERESTS

- Composing, recording, performing, and listening to music
- Researching and writing analytic philosophy
- Running
- Disc Golfing
- Fishing with my father